Finding Aid for the Collection of 19th-century European Sheet Music, circa 1791-1900
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Complete works, circa 1791-1900, I.; Items 1-125
  - West, W. Pet of the family polka Pet of the family: polka, between 1847 and 1868, 1 score (4 pages); Londond (England): B. Williams For voice and piano. "As performed with the greatest success at the Theatres Royal Haymarket and Adelphi" and "dedicated to his friend Benjn. Webster Esqr.". Color title page illustration: a little girl in a red dress and bonnet hugging a lamb with a red bandana around its neck. (Box 4, Item 120)
  - Westenholtz, Friedrich, 1778-1840 König Ankäos König Ankäos: ballade aus Natalia, circa 1800, 1 score (12 pages); Hamburg (Germany): I. A. Böhme For voice and piano. (Box 4, Item 121)
  - Winter, Peter von, 1754-1825 Ratto di Proserpina. Lieti fiori, ombrose piante; arranged Lieti fiori: a favorite air and glee as sung by Signora Grassini in the serious opera of Il Ratto di Proserpina, 1804, 1 score (6 pages); London (England): M. Kelly For three voices and piano. Lyricist: Da Ponte, Lorenzo, 1749-1838 Arranger: Mortellari, M. C. Engraved by J. Balls. (Box 4, Item 122)
  - Winter, Peter von, 1754-1825 Ratto di Proserpina. Mi lasci, o madre amata; arranged Mi lasci o madre amata: the much admir'd trio sung at the King's Theatre by Mrs. Billington, Sigr. Viganoni and Sigra. Grassini in the opera of Il Ratto di Proserpina, 1804, 1 score (6 pages); London (England): M. Kelly For three voices and piano. Lyricist: Da Ponte, Lorenzo, 1749-1838 Arranger: Mortellari, M. C. Engraved by J. Balls. (Box 4, Item 123)
  - Winter, Peter von, 1754-1825 Ratto di Proserpina. Ti veggo t'abbraccio; arranged Ti veggo t'abbraccio: the favorite duett sung at the King's Theatre by Mrs. Billington and Sigra. Grassini in the opera of Il Ratto di Proserpina, 1804, 1 score (8 pages); London (England): M. Kelly For two voices and piano. Lyricist: Da Ponte, Lorenzo, 1749-1838 Arranger: Mortellari, M. C. Engraved by J. Balls. (Box 4, Item 124)
  - Yradier, Sebastián, 1809-1865 Aÿ chiquita Aÿ chiquita: chanson espagnole chanter par Melle. Juliette Beau, 1875, 1 score (3 pages); Paris (France): Au Ménestrel For voice and piano. Lyricist: Bernard, Paul, 1827-1879 First page notes that there are two editions available, "No. 1. baryton ou contralto" and "No. 2. tenor ou soprano". This edition is for "ténor ou soprano". Composer's last name spelled "Iradier" various places on the music. Title page illustration: a decorated archway with a cross at the top surrounding the title / A. Barbizet. (Box 4, Item 125)
- Partial works, 1801-1895, II.; Items 126-149
  - Albert, Charles d', 1809-1886 Sultan's polka Sultan's polka by Chas. D'Albert, circa 1860, 1 title page and page 5 of music; London (England): Chappell Color title page illustration: A sultan next to his horse, before a background of tents, and turbanned figures on horseback (possibly as a part of the Crimean War) / J. Brandard. (Box 4, Item 126)
  - Arditi, Luigi, 1822-1903 Nearest way home Nearest way home: ballad, written by H. B. Farnie, composed by L. Arditi, 1868, 1 title page; London (England): Duff and Stewart "Sung by Mlle. Liebhart." Color title page illustration: A couple walking on a path near a water mill / Stannard and Dixon. (Box 4, Item 127)
  - Azote Titania waltz Titania waltz, by Azote, 1895, 1 title page; London (England): Orpheus Music Publishing Color title page illustration: Titania reclining on a bough within a floral frame. (Box 4, Item 128)
  - Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870 Bohemian girl. I dreamt that I dwelt in marble halls; arranged I dreamt that I dwelt in marble halls: song, sung by Miss Rainforth at the Theatre Royal Drury Lane in the opera of The Bohemian girl, written by Alfred Bunn, composed by M. W. Balfe, 1869, 1 title page; London (England): Chappell and Co. (Box 4, Item 129)
  - Blumenthal, Jacques Fleurs emblématiques. Primevère Primevère: no. 1 des Fleurs emblématiques, op. 21, pour le piano, par Jacques Blumenthal, circa 1850, 1 title page; Offenbach am Main (Germany): Jean André "A Madame la Baronne Lionel de Rothschild." Color title page illustration: oval wreath of flowers framing title. (Box 4, Item 130)
  - Coote, Charles, 1809-1880 Stirrup cup quadrille Stirrup cup: quadrille, composed by Charles Coote, circa 1865, 1 title page; London (England): Chappell and Co. Color title page illustration: a man on horseback accepting a goblet from a woman / Concanen, Lee, and Siebe, Lith. (Box 4, Item 131)
  - Coote, Charles, Jr. Pretty bird Pretty bird: valse … by C. Coote Junr., 1866, 1 title page; London (England): Hopwood and Crew Color title page illustration: portrait of a lady with a canary / Stannard and Dixon. (Box 4, Item 132)
  - Foster, Stephen Collins, 1826-1864 Willie we have missed you Illustrated American edition of Christy's Minstrels songs: Willie we have miss'd you, solo and chorus, circa 1860, 1 title page and page 5 of music; London (England): Foster and L'Enfant Title page illustration: soldier in uniform entering a house and taking the hand of a waiting woman. (Box 4, Item 133)
  - Fricker, Anne, 1820- I built a bridge of fancies I built a bridge of fancies: song, written by Miss Mylne, the music composed by Anne Fricker, 1855, 1 title page; London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. (Box 4, Item 134)
  - Gantier, Felix Zampa Operatic gems, no. 27: Zampa, circa 1867, 1 title page; London (England): Charles Jefferys Gantier (possibly a pseudonym) composed a series of fantasias on opera themes. This one is probably on Hérold's opera, Zampa. Color title page illustration: ship with broken mast in the Bay of Genoa with full moon in background / Packer and Griffin, Lith.; Stannard and Son. (Box 4, Item 135)
  - Godfrey, Dan. (Daniel), 1831-1903 Hilda waltz Hilda: waltz composed & dedicated to the Baroness Ferdinand de Rothschild, by Dan. Godfrey. B. M. Grenadier Guards, circa 1865, 1 title page; London (England): Chappell and Co. Color title page illustration: a woman holding a locket with a portrait within / M. and N. Hanhart, Lith. (Box 4, Item 136)
  - Harvey, R. F. (Richard Frederick) Build me a home of sparkling shells Build me a home of sparkling shells, written by S. Elrington, composed by Richard F. Harvey, 1869, 1 title page; London (England): John Blockley (Box 4, Item 137)
  - Lindsay, M., Miss Bridge Bridge, words by H. W. Longfellow, esq.; music by Miss M. Lindsay (Mrs. J. Worthington Bliss), 1867, 1 title page; London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. Color title page illustration: a bridge with cityscape in background with full moon. (Box 4, Item 138)
  - Lindsay, M., Miss Toilette de Constance Toilette de Constance, words by Casimir Delavigne, music by Miss M. Lindsay (Mrs. J. Worthington Bliss), 1869, 1 title page; London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. Color title page illustration: frame around title. (Box 4, Item 139)
  - Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 Belle Hélène. Mari sage; arranged Mari sage = When on his jaunts a husband wants: (no. 16): ballad, sung by Mlle. Schneider in the comic opera La belle Hélène; the English version by Charles Lamb Kenney; composed by J. Offenbach., 1868, 1 title page; London (England): Chappell and Co. (Box 4, Item 140)
  - Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880 Grand duchesse de Gerolstein. Selections; arranged Two selections from The Grand Duchess of Gerolstein": Lo! Here the sabre of my sire (song) and Oh! I dote on the military (rondo), 1869, 2 title pages; London (England): Boosey and Co. (Box 4, Item 141)
  - Paladilhe, Emile, 1844-1926 Mandolita Mandolita: souvenir de Rome, E. Paladilhe, 1871, 1 title page; Paris (France): G. Hartmann 2nd edition. Title page illustration: three men, one playing a mandolin, another a guitar / Stop. (Box 4, Item 142)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 Chœurs religieux. Charité; arranged Charité, musique de G. Rossini, circa 1850, 1 title page; Mainz (Germany): Fils de B. Schott Possibly for an edition of Liszt's arrangement for piano. Title page illustration: a nun assisting two children outside a house with a graveyard in the background. (Box 4, Item 143)
  - Salaman, Charles (Charles Kensington), 1814-1901 I arise from dreams of thee I arise from dreams of thee: serenade, in B flat, the poetry by Shelley; the music by Charles Salaman, 1869, 1 title page and page 2 of music; London (England): Ashdown and Parry Plate number: A & P. No. 3168. (Box 4, Item 144)
  - Smallwood, William Evensong Even song: for the piano forte, composed by W. Smallwood, 1863, 1 title page and page 5 of music; London (England): B. Williams Color title page illustration: waterfront with church and full moon in background / T. Packer, Lith. (Box 4, Item 145)
  - Stigelli, G. (Giorgio), 1815-1868 Schoensten Augen Schoensten Augen = The brightest eyes, von Heine, the translation by Mrs. Elde Darby, composed and dedicated to the Contesse Olga Poniatowska by G. Stigelli, 1867, 1 title page; London (England): Charles Jefferys (Box 4, Item 146)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900 O fair dove! O fond dove! O fair dove! O fond dove!: song, words by Jean Ingelow; music by Arthur S. Sullivan, 1868, 1 title page; London (England): Ashdown and Parry "To Miss Rachel Scott Russell." (Box 4, Item 147)
  - Woodward, G. M. (George Moutard), approximately 1760-1809 Olio of good breeding Olio of good breeding: with sketches illustrative of the modern graces!!, by G.M. Woodward, 1801, 1 title page; London (England): R. Ackermann Color title page illustration: a gentleman bowing to a lady. (Box 4, Item 148)
  - Wrighton, W. T. (William Thomas), 1816-1880 Songs. Selections Three songs: Grieve not for me; Her bright smile haunts me still; Liquid gem, 1867-1871, 3 title pages; London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. Title pages are impressed with decorative patterns. (Box 4, Item 149)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Piano music; Songs with piano
Genres
sheet music; sheet music covers